Caitlin Quattromani: The election of 2016 felt different.
كيتلين كوترماني: کانت انتخابات سنة 2016 مختلفة.
Political conversations with our family and friends
أظهرت نقاشاتنا السياسية مع العائلة والأصدقاء
uncovered a level of polarization
نوعاً من الانقسام الواضح في الآراء
that many of us had not previously experienced.
الذي لم يعرفه الكثير منّا من قبل.
People who we always thought were reasonable and intelligent
والناس الذين اعتقدنا دائما أنهم عقلاء وأذكياء
seemed like strangers.
بدوا وكأنهم غرباء.
We said to ourselves, "How could you think that?
فقلنا لأنفسنا: "كيف يمكن أن تعتقد ذلك؟
I thought you were smart."
ظننتك ذكيا".
Lauran Arledge: Caitlin and I met in the summer of 2011,
لورين أرلدج: التقيت كيتلين في صيف عام 2011،
and we bonded around being working moms
وترابطنا معاً كأمهات عاملات
and trying to keep our very energetic boys busy.
وكنا نحاول إبقاء أبنائنا شديدي الحيويّة مشغولين.
And we soon found out we had almost everything in common.
وسرعان ما اكتشفنا أننا نتشارك تقريبًا في كلّ شيء.
From our love of Colorado to our love of sushi,
من حبنا لـكولورادو إلى حبنا للسوشي،
there wasn't much we didn't agree on.
لم يكن هناك الكثير الذي لا نتفق عليه.
We also discovered that we share a deep love of this country
اكتشفنا أيضا أننا نتشارك في حبنا العميق لهذا البلد
and feel a responsibility to be politically active.
ونشعر بالمسؤولية بأن نكون ناشطتين سياسيّا.
But no one's perfect --
ولكن لا أحد مثالي،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and I soon found out two disappointing things about Caitlin.
وسرعان ما اكتشفت أمرين مخيّبين للآمال بخصوص كيتلين.
First, she hates camping.
أولا، أنها تكره التخييم.
CQ: I think camping is the worst.
كيتلين : أعتقد أنّ التخييم هو أسوء شيء.
LA: So there would not be any joint camping trips in our future.
لورين: لذلك لن يكون لنا أي رحلات تخييم مشتركة في المستقبل.
The second thing is that she's politically active all right --
الأمر الثاني، أنها ناشطة سياسيًا
as a conservative.
كمحافظة.
CQ: I may hate camping, but I love politics.
كيتلين: قد أكره التخييم، ولكني أحب السياسة.
I listen to conservative talk radio just about every day,
أنا أستمع إلى الخطاب المحافظ على الراديو كل يوم تقريبا،
and I've volunteered for a few different conservative political campaigns.
ولقد تطوعت لبعض الحملات السياسية المختلفة للحزب المحافظ.
LA: And I'd say I'm a little to the left,
لورين: وأنا أميل قليلا إلى اليسار،
like all the way to the left.
أعني إلى أقصى اليسار.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I've always been interested in politics.
كنت دائما مهتمة بالسياسة.
I was a political science major,
كنت متخصّصة في العلوم السياسية،
and I worked as a community organizer and on a congressional campaign.
وعملت كمنظمة أنشطة مجتمعية وكمنظمة لحملة كونغرس.
CQ: So as Lauran and I were getting to know each other,
كيتلين: عندما تعرّفت على لوران،
it was right in the middle of that 2012 presidential campaign,
كنا تمامًا في منتصف الحملة الرئاسية لعام 2012،
and most of our early political conversations
وكانت معظم محادثاتنا السياسية في البداية
were really just based in jokes and pranks.
تقتصر حقيقة على النكات والمزح.
So as an example, I would change Lauran's computer screen saver
على سبيل المثال، أن أغيّر شاشة كمبيوتر لورين
to a picture of Mitt Romney,
لصورة ميت رومني،
or she would put an Obama campaign magnet on the back of my car.
أو أن تضع هي صورة مغناطيسية لحملة أوباما على ظهر سيارتي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
LA: Car, not minivan.
لورين: سيارة، وليس ميني فان.
CQ: But over time, those conversations grew more serious
كيتلين: ولكن مع مرور الوقت، تطوّرت تلك المحادثات لتصبح أكثر جدية
and really became a core of our friendship.
وأصبحت حقًا أساس صداقتنا.
And somewhere along the line,
وفي وقت ما،
we decided we didn't want to have any topic be off limits for discussion,
كان قرارنا أن لا نعتبر أي موضوع ممنوع من المناقشة،
even if those topics pushed us way outside of our friendship comfort zone.
حتى لو عرضت تلك المواضيع صداقتنا لبعض الاوقات غير المريحة.
LA: And so to most of us,
لورين: وبالنسبة لمعظمنا،
political conversations are a zero-sum game.
المحادثات السياسية هي لعبة حصيلتها صفر.
There's a winner and there's a loser.
هناك فائز وهناك خاسر.
We go for the attack and we spot a weakness in someone's argument.
نحن نهاجم ونحدّد نقطة ضعف في الحجة التي يقدّمها شخص ما.
And here's the important part:
والجزء المهم هو:
we tend to take every comment or opinion that's expressed
أننا نميل إلى أخذ كل تعليق أو رأي على أنه
as a personal affront to our own values and beliefs.
إساءة شخصية لقيمنا ومعتقداتنا.
But what if changed the way we think about these conversations?
ولكن ماذا لو غيرنا طريقة تفكيرنا في هذه المحادثات؟
What if, in these heated moments,
ماذا لو في مثل هذه اللحظات الساخنة
we chose dialogue over debate?
اخترنا الحوار عوضًا عن الجدال؟
When we engage in dialogue, we flip the script.
وعندما نخوض حوارًا، نغيّر السيناريو.
We replace our ego and our desire to win
ونستبدل غرورنا ورغبتنا في الفوز
with curiosity, empathy
بالفضول والتعاطف
and a desire to learn.
والرغبة في التعلم.
Instead of coming from a place of judgment,
فبدلًا من القدوم بأحكام مسبقة،
we are genuinely interested in the other person's experiences,
نصبح مهتمين حقًا بتجارب الآخرين
their values and their concerns.
وقيمهم وشواغلهم.
CQ: You make it sound so simple, Lauran.
كيتلين: أنتِ تجعلين الأمر يبدو في غاية البساطة، لورين.
But getting to that place of true dialogue is hard,
ولكن الوصول إلى هذا المستوى من الحوار الحقيقي أمر صعب،
especially when we're talking about politics.
خاصة عندما نتحدث عن السياسة.
It is so easy to get emotionally fired up
فمن السهل جدًا أن نُستثار عاطفيًّا
about issues that we're passionate about,
حول القضايا التي نكون متحمسين لها،
and we can let our ego get in the way of truly hearing
ويمكن أن ندع اغترارنا بأنفسنا يحول دون سماعنا
the other person's perspective.
لوجهة نظر الشخص الآخر.
And in this crazy political climate we're in right now,
في هذا المناخ السياسي المجنون الذي نعيشه الآن،
unfortunately, we're seeing an extreme result
للأسف، نشهد نتيجة متطرفة
of those heated political conversations,
لتلك المحادثات السياسية الساخنة،
to the point where people are willing to walk away from their relationships.
إلى درجة أن الناس على استعداد للتخلي عن علاقاتهم.
In fact, Rasmussen released a poll earlier this year
في الواقع، أصدر راسموسن استطلاعا للرأي في وقت سابق من هذا العام
that said 40 percent of people reported that the 2016 election
بيّن أن 40 في المائة من الناس أفادوا أن انتخابات عام 2016
negatively impacted a personal relationship,
أثرت سلبًا على علاقة من علاقاتهم الشخصية،
and the Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience tells us
وتخبرنا مجلة علم الأعصاب الإدراكي
that people tend to feel their way to their beliefs
أن الناس يميلون إلى اتّباع مشاعرهم فيما يتعلق بقناعاتهم
rather than using reasoning,
أكثر من اعتمادهم على المنطق،
and that when reason and emotion collide,
وأنه عندما يتصادم العقل والعاطفة،
it's emotion that invariably wins.
فإن العاطفة تفوز دائمًا.
So no wonder it's hard to talk about these issues.
لذلك فلا عجب أنه من الصعب الحديث عن هذه القضايا.
LA: And look, we're just two regular friends
لورين: انظروا، نحن فقط صديقتان عاديّتان،
who happen to think very differently
صادف أننا نفكر بشكل مختلف جدًا
about politics and the role that government should play in our lives.
سياسيا وحول الدور الذي يجب أن تلعبه الحكومة في حياتنا.
And I know we were all taught not to talk about politics
وأنا أعلم أننا تعلمنا جميعًا أن لا نتحدث في السياسة
because it's not polite,
لأن ذلك ليس من التهذيب،
but we need to be able to talk about it,
ولكن علينا أن يكون بمقدورنا الحديث عنها،
because it's important to us and it's a part of who we are.
لأن ذلك مهم بالنسبة لنا، وهو جزء مما نحن عليه.
CQ: We have chosen to avoid political debate
كيتلين: لقد اخترنا تجنب الجدال السياسي
and instead engage in dialogue
وبدلًا من ذلك فضلنا الدخول في حوار
in order to maintain what we fondly call
من أجل الحفاظ على ما نسميه بكلّ شغف
our bipartisan friendship.
صداقة منقسمة بين حزبين.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
LA: And this election and all of the craziness that has followed
لورين: وهذه الانتخابات وكل الجنون الذي أعقبها
has given us several opportunities to practice this skill.
أعطانا العديد من الفرص لممارسة هذه المهارة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Let's start with January and the Women's March.
فلنبدأ بشهر يناير ومسيرة المرأة.
At this point, you can probably guess which one of us participated.
عند هذه النقطة، يمكنكم ربما أن تخمنوا من التي شاركت.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
CQ: Oh, the Women's March.
كيتلين: آه، مسيرة النساء.
I was annoyed and irritated that entire day,
كنت منزعجة وغاضبة كامل ذلك اليوم،
really because of two things.
حقًا بسبب أمرين اثنين.
Number one, the name "Women's March."
الأول، التسمية "مسيرة النّساء".
As a conservative woman,
فكامرأة محافظة،
the march's platform of issues didn't represent me,
جدول قضايا المسيرة لم يكن يمثلني،
and that's OK,
وهذا ليس بإشكال،
but hearing it talked about as this demonstration of sisterhood
ولكن سماع حديث أن التظاهرة كانت تظاهرة تآخي
and solidarity for all women
وتضامن بين جميع النساء
didn't ring true for me.
لم يكن صحيحًا بالنسبة إلّي.
The other piece was the timing of the event,
والأمر الآخر هو توقيت الحدث،
the fact that it was the day after the presidential inauguration.
وكونه كان في اليوم التالي لتولي الرئاسة.
It felt like we weren't even giving the new administration
شعرت أننا لم نعطي الإدارة الجديدة فرصة
to actually do anything, good or bad,
لتفعل أي شيء فعليا، سواء كان جيدًا أو سيئًا،
before people felt the need to demonstrate against it.
قبل أن يشعر الناس بالحاجة للتظاهر ضده.
LA: And under normal circumstances, I would agree with Caitlin.
لورين: في ظل الظروف العادية، كنت سأتفق مع كيتلين.
I think an administration does deserve the benefit of the doubt.
وأعتقد أن أي إدارة تستحق منحها الفرصة لمراجعة نفسها.
But in this case, I was marching to show my concern
ولكن في هذه الحالة، شاركت في هذه المسيرة لأبيّن قلقي
that a man with such a poor track record with women and other groups
من أن رجلًا له مثل هذا السجل الضعيف مع النّساء والمجموعات الأخرى
had been elected as president.
قد انتخب رئيسًا.
I had to be part of the collective voice
كان علي أن أكون جزءًا من الصوت الجماعي
that wanted to send a clear message to the new president
الذي أراد أن يرسل رسالة واضحة إلى الرئيس الجديد
that we did not accept or condone
بأننا لن نقبل أو نتغاضى
his behavior or rhetoric during the election.
عن سلوكه أو خطاباته أثناء الانتخابات.
CQ: So I'm already feeling kind of aggravated,
كيتلين: وقتها كنت أشعر بالغضب،
and then I see this Facebook from Lauran pop up in my social media feed.
ثم فجأة أرى هذا المنشور من لورين يظهر أمامي على الفيسبوك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Seeing Lauran's sons at the march and holding signs
عندما رأيت أبناء لورين في المسيرة ويرفعون الشعارات،
took it to a new level for me, and not in a good way,
شعرت بالتأثر، وليس بطريقة إيجابية،
because I know these boys,
لأنني أعرف هؤلاء الأولاد،
I love these boys,
وأنا أحب هؤلاء الأولاد،
and I didn't feel they were old enough
ولم أشعر أنهم كانوا ناضجين بما يكفي
to understand what the march stood for.
لفهم دوافع المسيرة.
I didn't understand why Lauran would choose
لم أفهم لماذا اختارت لورين
to have them participate in that way,
أن تجعلهم يشاركون بهذه المسيرة،
and I assumed it wasn't a choice that the boys made for themselves.
وافترضت أنه لم يكن خيارهم.
But I also know Lauran.
ولكنني أيضا أعرف لورين.
You're an incredible mom
أنت أم رائعة
who would never exploit your boys in any way,
والتي لا يمكنها أن تستغلّ أبناءها بأي شكل من الأشكال،
so I had to stop and check myself.
لذلك كان لا بدّ أن أتوقف وأراجع نفسي.
I had a decision to make.
كان عليّ أن أقرّر.
I could take the easy way out
إمّا أن أتّخذ الطريق السهل
and just choose not to say anything to her,
واختار عدم قول أي شيء لها،
and instead just kind of simmer in my frustration,
وبذلك نوعًا ما أكتم شعوري بالإحباط،
or I could ask her to learn more about her motivations.
أو أن أسألها وأحاول معرفة المزيد عن دوافعها.
LA: And I shared with Caitlin
لورين: وقلت لـكيتلين
that we actually started talking about the March
إننا بدأنا في الحديث عن المسيرة
weeks before we participated.
قبل أسابيع من مشاركتنا فيها.
And my boys were curious as to why the event was being organized,
وكان أولادي يشعرون بالفضول لمعرفة أسباب تنظيم هذا الحدث،
and this led to some very interesting family conversations.
وأدى ذلك إلى بعض النقاشات العائلية المثيرة جدًا.
We talked about how in this country, we have the right and the privilege
وتحدثنا عن أن كيف لنا الحق والامتياز في هذه الدولة
to demonstrate against something we don't agree with,
أن نتظاهر ضد أي شيء لا نتفق معه،
and my husband shared with them why he thought it was so important
وتحدث زوجي معهم عن سبب اعتقاده بأهمية
that men joined the Women's March.
أن ينضم الرجال إلى مسيرة المرأة.
But the most significant reason we marched as a family
ولكن أهم سبب وراء مشاركتنا في المسيرة كأسرة
is that it was a way for us to honor my parents' legacy.
هو أنها كانت وسيلة بالنسبة إلينا لتكريم موروث والديَّ.
They spent their careers
لقد أمضوا حياتهم المهنية
working to defend the rights of some of our most vulnerable citizens,
في الدفاع عن حقوق بعض مواطنينا الأكثر ضعفا،
and they passed these values down to me and my brother,
وقد مرروا هذه القيم إليّ وإلى أخي،
and we want to do the same with our sons.
ونريد أن نفعل الشيء نفسه مع أبنائنا.
CQ: After talking to Lauran,
كيتلين: بعد التحدث مع لورين،
I really understood not only why she felt it was so important to march,
تفهمت ليس فقط سبب شعورها بأهمية المشاركة في المسيرة،
but why she had her boys with her.
وإنما أيضا سبب اصطحابها لأولادها معها.
And frankly, my assumptions were wrong.
وبصراحة، كنت مخطئة في ما ظننت.
It was the boys who wanted to march
إذ كانت تلك رغبة الأبناء في المشاركة
after they talked about the issues as a family.
في المسيرة بعد أن تحدثوا كأسرة عن القضايا.
But what's most important about this example
ولكن أهم ما في هذا المثال
is to think about the alternative.
هو ضرورة التفكير في البديل.
Had Lauran and I not talked about it,
لو أن لورين وأنا لم نتحدث في ذلك،
I would have been annoyed with her,
لكنت قد انزعجت منها،
and it could have resulted in an undercurrent of disrespect
وكان يمكن أن يؤدي ذلك إلى الكثير من عدم الاحترام
in our friendship.
في صداقتنا.
But by asking Lauran questions, it allowed us to use dialogue
ولكن من خلال طرح أسئلة على لورين، استطعنا استخدام الحوار
to get to a place of true understanding.
للوصول إلى تفاهم حقيقي بيننا.
Now, to be clear,
والآن، لنكن واضحين،
our conversation didn't really change my mind about how I felt about the March,
لم يغير حديثنا حقًا رأيي حول المسيرة،
but it absolutely changed my thinking around why she brought her boys with her.
ولكنه غير تفكيري تماما بخصوص سبب اصطحابها لأولادها معها.
And for both of us, that dialogue allowed us to understand
وفي رأينا، سمح لنا هذا الحوار
each other's perspective about the Women's March
أن نفهم وجهة نظر بعضنا البعض بخصوص مسيرة المرأة
even though we disagreed.
على الرغم من اختلافنا.
LA: The second topic that challenged our ability to engage in dialogue
لورين: الموضوع الثاني الذي مثل تحديًا لقدرتنا على المشاركة في الحوار
was around my need to understand
كان حول حاجتي لفهم
how Caitlin could vote for Trump.
كيف استطاعت كيتلين التصويت لصالح ترامب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Caitlin is a successful professional woman
كيتلين هي امرأة مهنية وناجحة
who is deeply caring and compassionate,
وهي إنسانة متعاطفة للغاية،
and the Caitlin I know
وكيتلين التي أعرفها
would never excuse any man from talking about women
لن تسامح أبدا أي رجل لحديثه عن المرأة
the way that Trump did during the campaign.
بالطريقة التي تحدث بها ترامب أثناء الحملة.
It was hard for me to reconcile these two things in my mind.
كان من الصعب بالنسبة إلي التوفيق بين هذين الأمرين في ذهني.
How could you overlook the things that were said?
كيف يمكن أن تتجاهلي الأشياء التي قيلت؟
CQ: So I'm guessing I may not be the only one here that thought
كيتلين: في الحقيقة أظنٌ أنني لست الوحيدة هنا التي تعتقد
we didn't have the best choices for the presidential election last year.
أنه لم يكن لدينا أفضل الخيارات في الانتخابات الرئاسية العام الماضي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The Republican candidate who I did support didn't make it out of the primary,
المرشح الجمهوري الذي قمت بدعمه لم يفز بالمرحلة الأولية.
so when it came time to vote, I had a decision to make.
لذلك عندما حان وقت التصويت، كان عليّ أن أقرر.
And you're right, there were some terrible things
أنت على حق، كانت هناك بعض الأشياء الرهيبة
that came out during the Trump campaign,
التي وقعت خلال حملة ترامب،
so much so that I almost decided to just abstain
لدرجة أنني قررت تقريبًا الامتناع
rather than voting for president,
عن التصويت للرئيس،
something I had never even considered doing before.
وهو شيء لم أكن أعتقد بالمرة من قبل أنني سأقوم به.
But ultimately, I did vote for Donald Trump,
ولكن في نهاية المطاف، صوّتت لصالح دونالد ترامب،
and for me it was really a vote for party over person,
وبالنسبة إليّ كان ذلك تصويتًا للحزب وليس للشخص،
especially recognizing how important that presidential pick is
و كان خاصة اعترافا بأهمية هذا الاختيار
on influencing our judicial branch.
في التأثير على فرعنا القضائي.
But I shared with Lauran it was a decision I really wrestled with,
لكنني اتفقت مع لورين أنه كان قرارًا صعبًا حقًا،
and not one that I made lightly.
وليس قرارًا اتّخذته بسهولة.
LA: And so after our conversation, I was struck by a few things.
لورين: وهكذا بعد حديثنا، أدهشتني بعض الأشياء.
First, I had fallen victim to my own confirmation bias.
أولًا، لقد وقعت ضحية لتحيزي الخاص.
Because of my strong feelings about Trump,
بسبب مشاعري القوية بخصوص ترامب،
I had given all Trump voters the same attributes,
نعتٌّ جميع ناخبي ترامب بنفس الصفات،
and none of them forgiving.
ولم تكن أي صفة منهم متسامحة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But knowing Caitlin, I started to ask questions.
لكن بما أنني أعرف كيتلين، بدأت أطرح العديد من الأسئلة؛
What were Trump voters really concerned about?
ما الذي كان يقلق حقًا ناخبي ترامب؟
Under all the divisive language, what was really going on?
ماذا تخفي كل تلك اللغة المثيرة للانقسام؟
What could we learn about ourselves and our country
ماذا يمكننا أن نتعلم بخصوص أنفسنا وبلدنا
from this unlikely event?
من هذا الحدث غير المتوقع؟
I also learned that we shared a deep disappointment in this election,
وتعلمت أيضا أننا تشاركنا بخيبة أمل عميقة في هذه الانتخابات،
and that we have growing concerns about our two-party political system.
وأن لدينا مخاوف متزايدة بشأن نظامنا السياسي القائم على حزبين.
But the most important thing about this conversation
ولكن الشيء الأكثر أهمية في هذه المحادثة
is that it happened at all.
هو مجرد وقوعها.
Without an open and honest dialogue between the two of us,
وبدون حوار مفتوح وصادق بيننا،
this election would have been the elephant in the room
كانت هذه الانتخابات ستكون المشكلة الواضحة
for the next four years, pun intended.
طيلة السنوات الأربع القادمة، والتورية مقصودة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
CQ: So, look --
لذا، انظروا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So, look -- we know it takes work to get past the difficult,
لذا، انظروا، نحن نعلم أن الأمر يتطلب الجهد لتخطي
frustrating and sometimes emotional parts
الأجزاء الصعبة والمحبطة وأحيانا العاطفية
of having discussions about issues like the Women's March
عند إجراء مناقشات حول قضايا مثل مسيرة المرأة
or why your friend may have voted for a candidate that you can't stand.
أو سبب تصويت صديقك لمرشح لا تطيقه.
But we need to have these conversations.
لكننا بحاجة لهذه المحادثات.
Our ability to move past political debate
إن قدرتنا على تحويل النقاش السياسي
into true dialogue
إلى حوار حقيقي
is a critical skill we should all be focused on right now,
مهارة مهمة ينبغي أن نركز عليها جميعا الآن.
especially with the people that we care about the most.
خاصة مع الأشخاص الذين نهتم لأمرهم كثيرًا.
LA: And it's not just as adults that we need to bottle this behavior.
لورين: وليس الكبار فقط من هم في حاجة إلى اكتساب هذا السلوك.
It's critical that we do it for our children as well.
إذ من المهم جدا أن نكسبه لأطفالنا أيضا.
My sons were inundated with this election.
لقد أشغلت هذه الانتخابات أبنائي.
We were listening to the news in the morning,
كنا نستمع إلى الأخبار في الصباح،
and they were having conversations with their friends at school.
ثم يجرون محادثات مع أصدقائهم في المدرسة.
I was concerned that they were picking up so much polarizing misinformation,
شعرت بالقلق لأنهم كانوا يتلقون الكثير من المعلومات المضللة والمستقطبة،
and they were growing really fearful of a Trump presidency.
وكان تخوّفهم من رئاسة ترامب يتزايد.
Then one day, after the election, I was taking my sons to school,
ثم بعد يوم واحد، من الانتخابات، عندما كنت أوصل أبنائي إلى المدرسة،
and my younger son, completely out of the blue,
قال ابني الأصغر فجأة:
said, "Mom, we don't know anybody who voted for Trump, right?"
"أمي، نحن لا نعرف أي شخص صوَّت لـترامب، أليس كذلك؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I paused and I took a deep breath.
صمت للحظة وأخذت نفسًا عميقًا.
"Yes, we do."
"لا، بل نعرف."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"The Quattromanis."
عائلة كواتروماني.
And his response was so great.
وكان رده رائعًا جدًّا.
He kind of got this confused look on his face, and he said ...
وبدى على وجهه الارتباك، ثم قال،
"But we love them."
"لكننا نحبهم".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I answered, "Yes, we do."
وأجبت: "نعم، نحبهم".
And then he said, "Why would they vote for him?"
ثم قال: "لماذا قاموا بالتصويت له؟"
And I remember stopping and thinking
وأتذكر أني توقّفت للحظة وفكرت
that it was really important how I answered this question.
في أن طريقة إجابتي على هذا السؤال هي حقا مهمّة.
Somehow, I had to honor our own family values
وبطريقة أو بأخرى، كان علي أن أٌكرّم قيمنا العائلية
and show respect for our friends.
وأظهر الاحترام لأصدقائنا.
So I finally said,
فقلت أخيرًا،
"They think that's the right direction for this country."
"إنهم يعتقدون أن هذا هو الاتجاه الصحيح لهذا البلد".
And before I had even gotten the whole sentence out,
وقبل أن أنهي جملتي،
he had moved on to the soccer game he was going to play at recess.
انتقل إلى موضوع لعبة كرة القدم التي كان سيلعبها في العطلة.
CQ: So life with boys.
تلك هي الحياة مع الأولاد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So what Lauran and I have discovered through our bipartisan friendship
كيتلين: فما اكتشفه أنا ولورين من خلال صداقتنا المنقسمة بين حزبين
is the possibility that lives in dialogue.
هو إمكانية التعايش بالحوار.
We have chosen to be genuinely curious
وقد اخترنا أن يكون لدينا فضول حقيقيّ
about each other's ideas and perspectives
بشأن أفكار ووجهات نظر بعضنا البعض
and to be willing to listen to one another even when we disagree.
وأن نكون على استعداد للاستماع إلى بعضنا البعض حتى عند الاختلاف.
And by putting aside our ego and our preconceived ideas,
وبوضع نرجسيّتنا وأفكارنا المسبقة جانبا،
we've opened ourselves up to limitless learning.
جعلنا منفتحتين على تعلّم لا حدود له.
And perhaps most importantly for our relationship,
وربما الأهم من ذلك بالنسبة لعلاقتنا،
we have made the commitment to each other
هو التزامنا تجاه بعضنا
that our friendship is way more important
بأن تكون صداقتنا أكثر أهمية
than either of us being right or winning a conversation about politics.
من كون أحدنا على صواب أو أن تفوز في جدال سياسي.
So today, we're asking you to have a conversation.
إذن اليوم نحن نطلب منكم أن تجروا محادثة.
Talk to someone outside of your political party
أن تتحدثوا إلى شخص لا ينتمي إلى حزبك السياسي
who might challenge your thinking.
والذي قد يجادلك الرأي.
Make an effort to engage with someone
وابذلوا جهدًا للتعامل مع شخص
with whom you might typically avoid a political conversation.
عادة ما تتجنب الحديث معه في السياسة.
But remember, the goal isn't to win,
ولكن تذكر أن الهدف ليس الفوز،
the goal is to listen and to understand
وإنما الاستماع والفهم
and to be open to learning something new.
والانفتاح على تعلم شيء جديد.
LA: So let's go back to election night.
لورين: إذن، دعونا نعود إلى ليلة الانتخابات.
As the polls were closing
ومع اقتراب نهاية الاقتراع،
and it became clear that Trump was going to be our new president,
والتأكد من أن ترامب سيصبح رئيسنا الجديد،
I was devastated.
كنت منهارة.
I was sad, I was confused,
كنت حزينة، كنت في حيرة،
and I'll be honest -- I was angry.
وأصدقكم القول، كنت غاضبة.
And then just before midnight,
ثم مباشرة قبل منتصف الليل،
I received this text message from Caitlin.
تلقيت هذه الرسالة النصية من كيتلين.
[I know this is a hard night for you guys.
[أعرف أن هذه ليلة صعبة بالنسبة إليكم.
We are thinking of you. Love you.]
نحن نفكر بكم. أحبكم].
And where there so easy could have been weeks or months of awkwardness
وحيث كان هناك أسابيع أو أشهر من الحرج
and unspoken hostility, there was this --
والعداء المسكوت عنه، كان هناك أيضا،
an offering of empathy rooted in friendship.
تعاطف متأصل في الصداقة.
And I knew, in that moment, that we would make it through this.
وعرفت في تلك اللحظة، أننا سوف نتجاوز هذه الأزمة.
CQ: So we must find a way to engage in meaningful conversations
كيتلين: ولذلك يجب علينا أن نجد طريقه للانخراط في محادثات هادفة
that are going to move us forward as a nation,
تدفعنا قدمًا كأمة واحدة،
and we can no longer wait
ولا يمكننا أن ننتظر بعد الآن
for our elected officials to elevate our national discourse.
أن يرفع مسؤولونا المنتخبون خطابنا الوطني.
LA: The challenges ahead are going to require all of us
لورين: ستتطلب التحديات المقبلة منا جميعاً
to participate in a deeper and more meaningful way ...
أن نشارك بطريقة أعمق وأكثر جدوى...
and it starts with each one of us
وذلك بأن يشرع كل واحد منا
building connection through dialogue --
في بناء التواصل باستعمال الحوار
in our relationships, our communities
في علاقاتنا ومجتمعاتنا
and as a country.
وبلدنا ككل.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)